Finding aid to the Smith College Staff Council records CA.MS.00035
Smith College Archives
Smith College Staff Council records
1984-[ongoing]
Smith College Archives
Smith College. Staff Council.
CA.MS.00035
4 boxes
The collection contains the papers of the Staff Council, a College organization, including agendas, meeting minutes, correspondence, and newsletters.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.
Additions to the Collection
Additions to these records arrive in the College Archives on a regular baisis. Please contact the College Archives for the most up-to-date information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records of the Smith College Staff Council were delivered to the College Archives over several years by the various Chairs of the Staff Council.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith College Staff Council was initiated in 1991 by administrative and support staff concerned about the lack of communication among the staff and administration. Several Staff Council Conventions were held during the later part of 1991 and early 1992 to work out the mission and duties of the Staff Council. The charter was approved by the Board of Trustees at their May 2, 1992 meeting.
The mission of the Staff Council as stated in the charter is: "to give members of the administrative, administrative support, and service staff a focused and direct involvement in the governance of non-academic affairs and in the life of the Smith College community." The Staff Council works to enhance communication between employees and the College and examines policies that affect the workplace environment making recommendations to the College. It accomplishes this task through six standing committees: Steering, Nominations and Elections, Communication, Personnel Policy, Staff Development and Finance and Budget. In addition to committee work the Staff Council also publishes a newsletter, currently called The Council Chronicle, as its vehicle to keep staff informed of issues and events.
Scope and Contents
The Staff Council records occupy .6 linear feet and consist primarily of agendas, meeting minutes of the Staff Council and its standing and ad-hoc committees and the attendant correspondence. The materials range in date from 1984 to 2001 with the bulk of the materials concentrated in the years 1993-1996. A complete set of the newsletter, The Council Chronicle, is also available in this collection of materials.
Smith College. Staff Council.; Smith College--Administration.
- Budget, 1993-94 (Box 646.3)
- Committees - At Large, 1993-94 (Box 646.3)
- Committees - Communications, 1993-94 (Box 646.3)
- Committees - Finance and Budget, 1992-94 (Box 646.3)
- Committees - Nominations and Elections, 1992-93 (Box 646.3)
- Committees - Nominations and Elections, 1993-94 (Box 646.3)
- Committees - Nominations and Elections, 1994-95 (Box 646.3)
- Committees - Personnel Policy, 1993-94 (Box 646.3)
- Committees - Recreation, 1993-94 (Box 646.3)
- Committees - Staff Development, 1992-94 (Box 646.3)
- Committees - Steering, 1992-96 (Box 646.3)
- Correspondence, 1992-93 (Box 646.3)
- Correspondence, 1993-94 (Box 646.3)
- Correspondence, 1994-95 (Box 646.3)
- Correspondence, 1995-96 (Box 646.3)
- Correspondence, 1996-97 (Box 646.3)
- Forums, 1992-95 (Box 646.3)
- Labor Organization, 1993 (Box 646.3)
- Meetings - Formation, 1991-92 (Box 646.3)
- Meetings, 1992-93 (Box 646.3)
- Meetings, 1993-94 (Box 647)
- Meetings, 1994-95 (Box 647)
- Meetings, 1995-96 (Box 647)
- Meetings, 1996-97 (Box 647)
- Meetings, 1997-98 (Box 647)
- Newsletter Editorial Board, 1993 (Box 647)
- Newsletter - Staff Council Newsletter vol. 1, March 1993 (Box 647)
- Newsletter - Council Chronicle vol. 2, May 1993 - May 1997 (Box 647)
- Newsletter - Council Chronicle, Aug 1997 - Nov 1999 (Box 647)
- Newsletter - Council Chronicle, Jan 2000 - present (Box 647)
- Staff groups at other institutions, 1984-91; undated (Box 647)
- Staff/Student Relationships Policy, 1993-94 (Box 647)
- Workshops, 1993 (Box 647)
- Staff Council's Staff Visions Committee records, 1993-2006 (Box 647.1, Box 647.2)